神父 到目前 你应该很清楚
Come now, Father, you should know better.
这里并不欢迎你 特别是今天
You're not welcome here, and especially not today.
我没时间再跟你争论
I've got no time to start old arguments.
我们只要一样东西
We want only one thing.
想要什么
And what would that be?
这座房子
This house.
你想要这座房子
You want the house?
我们会接管这房子
We will take the house.
你怎么不连我老婆也接管得了
Would you like my wife while you're at it?
如果你们不靠边站 我们只好强制夺下
If you won't stand aside, then we'll take it by force.
用什么夺 上帝之手吗
And by what power? The hand of God?
不
No,
用拳头
the fist of man.
老天爷啊
In the name of Heaven.
夫人
My Lady?
那里面是什么东西
What's in there?
那是什么 帆布下是什么东西
What is it? What's under the canvas?
神父 回答我 那是什么东西
Father, answer me. What's in there?
愿上帝原谅我
May God forgive me.
你觉得这件怎么样 还行吗
What do you think of this? Will it do?
在70年代末期 这么穿还不如套个垃圾袋
The late 1970s? You'd be better off in a bin bag.
等等 听听这个
Hold on, listen to this.
伊恩·杜瑞和木头人 1979年第一热门
Ian Dury and The Blockheads. Number one in 1979.
你是个朋克
You're a punk!
那就是你的类型了
That's what you are,
一个混合了乡村摇滚乐风格的老朋克
That's what you are, a big old punk with a bit of rockabilly thrown in.
你想去看看他吗
Do you want to go and see him?
你是说去演唱会吗
How do you mean, in concert?
不然要塔迪斯做什么
What else is the Tardis for?
我能带你去特拉法尔加战役
I can take you to the Battle of Trafalgar,
第一届反重力奥运会
the First Antigravity Olympics,
凯撒穿越卢比肯河
Caesar crossing the Rubicon
或者
or...
去1979年11月21日 看伊恩·杜瑞
Ian Dury at the Top Rank, Sheffield,
在地球-英格兰-谢菲尔德市的演唱会
England, Earth, 21st November 1979,
你觉得怎么样
what do you think?
那就谢菲尔德好了
Sheffield it is!
抓紧了
Hold on tight.
啊……着陆了
Landing!
1979年 见鬼的一年
1979! Hell of a year!
中国入侵越南
China invades Vietnam.
《布偶大电影》我喜欢这部电影
The Muppet Movie, love that film.
玛格丽特·撒切尔
Margaret Thatcher.
SKYLAB卫星着陆 我帮了点忙
Skylab falls to Earth with a little help from me.
差点要了我的拇指 我爱我的拇指
Nearly took off my thumb, and I like my thumb.
我需要我的拇指 我很依赖
I need my thumb. I'm very attached to..
我的拇指
my thumb.
1879年 半斤八两
1879. Same difference.
解释一下你的来路
You will explain your presence,
以及这个女子为何穿着暴露
and the nakedness of this girl.
我们是在苏格兰吗
Are we in Scotland?
你怎么能连这个都不知道
How can you be ignorant of that?
噢 我有点眼花缭乱 糊涂了
I'm dazed and confused.
我一直在跋山涉水的追踪这个暴露的丫头
I've been chasing this wee naked child over hill and over dale.
对吧…你这个野姑娘
Isn't that right, you timorous beastie?
哦 是的
Och, aye.
我一直在外面蹦跶
I've been "oot" and "aboot."
不 别用这种调调
No, don't do that.
怎么了
Hoots, mon?
不 真的别这样
No, really don't. Really.
说明一下你的身份 先生
Will you identify yourself, sir?
我是詹姆斯·麦克里蒙博士
I'm Doctor James McCrimmon
来自巴拉莫瑞小镇
from the township of Balamory.
我有证书 我能否
I have my credentials, if I may?
如你所见 爱丁堡大学的博士
As you can see, a doctorate from the University of Edinburgh.
我是贝尔博士的学生
I trained under Doctor Bell himself.
让他们过来
WOMAN: Let them approach.
我不认为那是明智之举 夫人
I don't think that's wise, ma'am.
让他们过来
Let them approach.
你们可以靠近马车了
You will approach the carriage,
表现出应有的尊敬
and show all due deference.
洛斯
Rose,
我为你介绍维多利亚女王殿下
might I introduce Her Majesty Queen Victoria,
印度女皇 "信仰捍卫者"
Empress of India and Defender of the Faith.
我是洛斯·泰勒 陛下
Rose Tyler, ma'am.
抱歉…我穿得那么少
And my apologies for being so naked.
我有五个女儿 这对我来说没什么
I've had five daughters. It's nothing to me.
但你 博士 给我看看这些证书
But you, Doctor, show me these credentials.
你为什么不早说呢
Why didn't you say so immediately?
这很清楚地写着
It states clearly here
大市长指定你为我的保护者
that you have been appointed by the Lord Provost as my protector.
是吗 是的没错 很好
Does it? Yes, it does. Good. Good.
那么容我问问
Erm, then let me ask,
为什么陛下由陆路旅行
why is Your Majesty travelling by road
不是有条直达阿伯丁的铁路吗
when there's a train all the way to Aberdeen?
铁路上有棵树
A tree on the line.
是意外吗
An accident?
我是大不列颠及爱尔兰联合王国的女王
I am the Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland.
和我有关的事情都不会是意外
Everything around me tends to be planned.
有人企图刺杀吗
An assassination attempt?
什么 真的吗 有人想要刺杀你
What, seriously? There's people out to kill you?
我都习惯于被人用枪筒瞄着了
I'm quite used to staring down the barrel of a gun.
罗伯特·麦克利什爵士就住在十英里外
Sir Robert MacLeish lives but 10 miles hence.
我们已经先通传过了
We've sent word ahead.
他会招待我们一晚 然后我们明天将抵达巴尔摩洛
He'll shelter us for tonight, then we can reach Balmoral tomorrow.
这博士和他的"野丫头"将随同我们
This Doctor and his timorous beastie will come with us.
好的 陛下
Yes, ma'am.
我们最好继续前进 天快黑了
We'd better get moving. It's almost nightfall.
确实 而且这里有很多关于狼的传说
Indeed, and there are stories of wolves in these parts.
都是些虚构的故事 用来吓唬小孩的
Fanciful tales, intended to scare the children,
但我认为有助血液循环 启程
but good for the blood, I think. Drive on.
挺有趣的 因为说起刺杀
It's funny, though, 'cause you say assassination,
人们通常会想起肯尼迪事件 而不是她
and you just think of Kennedy and stuff, not her.
1879年 她已经遭遇过
1879? She's had,
六次刺杀企图了
six attempts on her life.
而且 我跟你说件事
And I'll tell you something else.
我们刚刚见了维多利亚女王
We just met Queen Victoria.
我知道
I know!
多有趣
What a laugh!
她就坐在那里
She was just sitting there!
跟邮票一样
Like a stamp.
我想让她说"这并不好笑"
I want her to say, "We are not amused."
和你赌五镑 我能让她说这句话
I bet you 5 quid I can make her say it.
如果我跟你赌
Well, if I gambled on that,
那就是在滥用时间旅行者的特权
it would be an abuse of my privilege as a traveller in time.
十镑
10 quid.
成交
Done.
我不能这么做 这是叛国
I can't do this. It's treason.
那你妻子就会承受你的后果
Then your wife will suffer the consequences.
相信我 罗伯特爵士
Believe me, Sir Robert,
她会被吞噬的
she will be devoured.
陛下
Your Majesty.
罗伯特爵士
Sir Robert.
抱歉因为紧急事件打搅到你
My apologies for the emergency.
伊莎贝尔夫人怎么了
And how is Lady Isobel?
她
She's...
不太舒服
indisposed,
她已出发去爱丁堡住一个季节
I'm afraid She's gone to Edinburgh for the season,
她把厨师也带走了 厨房的储蓄都快没了
and she's taken the cook with her, the kitchens are barely stocked.
如果您不愿屈身下住 我能理解 陛下
I wouldn't blame Your Majesty if you wanted to ride on.
不用这样想 我已饱尝乘车之旅了
Not at all. I've had quite enough carriage exercise,
这里挺迷人的 很质朴
and this is charming, if rustic.
这是我第一次拜访这房子
It's my first visit to this house.
我前夫经常提起这里
My late husband spoke of it often,
火炬木之馆
the Torchwood Estate.
现在可以进去了吗
Now, shall we go inside?
请原谅这裸露的女子
And please excuse the naked girl.
抱歉
Sorry!
她是个野孩子
She's a feral. child.
我在旧伦敦镇花六便士买来的
I bought her for sixpence in old London town.
不买她也只能买到四不像了
It was her or the Elephant Man, so...
他觉得自己挺搞笑的 但我觉得并不好笑
Thinks he's funny, but I'm so not amused.
你认为呢 陛下
What do you think, ma'am?
这无关紧要 我们能先进去吗
It hardly matters. Shall we proceed?
就差一点
So close.
麦克森和拉姆齐 你们来护送这物品 快
Mackeson and Ramsay, you will escort the property. Hurry up.
是的 队长
Yes, sir.
那里面是什么东西啊
So what's in there, then?
皇家的东西
Property of the Crown.
你不能乱打主意 先生
You will dismiss any further thoughts, sir.
其余的人 到后面去
The rest of you, go to the rear of the house.
按指定就位
Assume the designated positions.
你们听到命令了 就位
You heard the orders, positions.
先生
Sir.
用你们的生命来守护好它
Guard it with your life.
我猜这就是著名的"奋进号"了吧
This, I take it, is the famous endeavour.
都是我父亲的作品
All my father's work.
在他晚年亲手建造的
Built by hand in his final years.
他渐渐沉迷其中
It became something of an obsession.
他花在这上面的钱 比花在房子和自己身上的还多
He spent his money on this, rather than caring for the house or himself.
真希望能见到他 我喜欢他
I wish I'd met him. I like him.
那东西好漂亮 我能不能
That thing's beautiful, can I...
请自便
Help yourself.
他在仿造什么
What did he model it on?
我对这些一无所知
I know nothing about it.
老实说 我们大部分人都觉得他
To be honest, most of us thought him a little,
精神失常吧 可以说
shall we say, eccentric.
现在我希望能花多点时间陪陪他
I wish now I'd spent more time with him
倾听他的故事
and listened to his stories.
这有点糟糕啊
It's a bit rubbish.
这里面装了多少棱镜 太多了吧
How many prisms has it got? Way too many!
这放大倍率实在是太过了 真是个愚蠢之举
The magnification's gone right over the top. That's a stupid kind of...
我是不是又很没礼貌
Am I being rude again?
是的
Yeah.
但是造型很不错 非常
But it's pretty, very...
精美
pretty
并且其想象力很值得称赞
And the imagination of it should be applauded.
我认为你不会赞成 陛下
Hmm. I thought you might disapprove, Your Majesty.
夜观天象 是不是有些天方夜谈了
Stargazing. Isn't that a bit fanciful?
你可能觉得不好笑…之类的 没有吗
You could easily not be amused, or something. No?
这装置是用来观察广阔无穷的造物的
This device surveys the infinite work of God.
还有什么比这更出色的
What could be finer?
罗伯特爵士的父亲是我们的榜样
Sir Robert's father was an example to us all,
他博学多识 在天文学和自然科学方面成就很高
a polymath, steeped in astronomy and the sciences,
同时对民间传说和童话故事也很有研究
yet equally well-versed in folklore and fairytales.
星空和魔法 我越来越喜欢他了
Stars and magic. I like him more and more.
噢 我前夫很喜欢与他作伴
Oh, my late husband enjoyed his company.
阿尔伯特王子本身对乡间迷信很感兴趣
Prince Albert himself was acquainted with many rural superstitions,
好像他就来自萨克森-科堡似的
coming as he did from Saxe-Coburg.
那是巴伐利亚
That's Bavaria.
当阿尔伯特听说你们当地狼的故事时
When Albert was told about your local wolf,
他欣喜不已
he was transported.
这只狼是怎么回事
So what's this wolf, then?
只是个故事而已
It's just a story.
那就说来听听
Then tell it.
传说
It's said that...
打扰了 阁下
Excuse me, sir.
也许陛下的故事还是回房再说吧
Perhaps Her Majesty's party could repair to their rooms.
现在天色已晚了
It's almost dark.
当然 是的 当然
Of course. Yes, of course.
那就用餐吧
And then supper.
能找些衣服给这位泰勒小姐吗
And could we find some clothes for Miss Tyler?
我都快看烦了
I'm tired of nakedness.
这并不好玩 不是吗
It's not amusing, is it?
罗伯特阁下 你妻子一定留了些衣服 找找看
Sir Robert, your wife must have left some clothes. See to it.
我们七点用餐 然后再多讲讲狼的故事
We shall dine at 7:00, and talk some more of this wolf.
毕竟 今晚是个月圆之夜
After all, there is a full moon tonight.
确实如此 陛下
So there is, ma'am.
他们悄无声息地进入这房子
They came through the house in silence.
把管家 主人和女主人都带走了
They took the steward and the master, and my lady.
听着 我有个朋友
Listen, I've got a friend.
他叫做博士 他知道该怎么做
He's called the Doctor. He'll know what to do.
你得跟我来
You've got to come with me.
但我不能 小姐
Oh, but I can't, Miss.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
弗洛拉
Flora.
弗洛拉 我们会没事的
Flora, we'll be safe.
楼下来了很多人 还有许多士兵
There's more people arrived downstairs, soldiers and everything.
他们能帮我们 我保证
They can help us. I promise.
来吧 好吗 跟我来
Come on. Okay? Come on.
噢 小姐 我提醒过你了
Oh, Miss, I did warn you.
他没死 我觉得没死 他一定被下药了之类的
He's not dead, I don't think. He must be drugged or something.
你的同伴说抱歉 博士
Your companion begs an apology, Doctor.
她的衣着稍微耽误了她
Her clothing has somewhat delayed her.
没关系的 给她留点火腿好了
Oh, that's all right. Save her a wee bit of ham.
那野孩子可能连生肉都能吃
The feral child could probably eat it raw.
非常机智 陛下 非常幽默
Very wise, ma'am. Very witty.
略微有点吧 只能说
Slightly witty, perhaps.
我知道你很少机会能和我进餐 队长
I know you rarely get the chance to dine with me, Captain,
但不要显得太兴奋了
but don't get too excited.
我还是少机智一点 以防你呛到了
I shall contain my wit in case I do you further injury.
是的 陛下 抱歉 陛下
Yes, ma'am. Sorry, ma'am.
我们都在等罗伯特爵士 来吧 爵士
Besides, we're all waiting on Sir Robert. Come, sir.
你答应过要讲一个梦魇般的故事
You promised us a tale of nightmares.
确实
VICTORIA: Indeed.
自从我的前夫去世了
Since my husband's death,
我发现自己对超自然的故事更有兴趣了
I find myself with more of a taste for supernatural fiction.
你一定很想念他
You must miss him.
非常想念
Very much.
噢 十分想念
Oh, completely.
那就是鬼故事迷人之处 不是吗
And that's the charm of a ghost story, isn't it?
不在于惊吓或恐怖 那些都是给小孩听的
Not the scares and chills, that's just for children,
而是在于与自然世界之外产生联系的希望
but the hope of some contact with the great beyond.
我们都希望能收到一点外界的信息
We all want some message from that place.
是造物主最大的奥秘 让我们得不到慰藉
It's the Creator's greatest mystery that we're allowed no such consolation.
逝者不能复生
The dead stay silent,
而我们只能等待
and we must wait.
来吧 开始讲故事吧 罗伯特爵士
Come, begin your tale, Sir Robert.
气氛正合适呢
There's a chill in the air.
风正呼啸着穿越屋檐 给我们说点怪物的事吧
The wind is howling through the eaves. Tell us of monsters.
不要出声
Don't make a sound.
如果我们大喊大叫 他会把我们宰掉的
They said if we scream or shout, then he will slaughter us.
但…他关在笼子里
But he's in a cage.
他是个囚犯 他和我们一样
He's a prisoner. He's the same as us.
他和我们不一样
He's nothing like us.
那生物不是正常人
That creature is not mortal.
故事追溯到三百年前
The story goes back 300 years.
每到月圆之时 嚎叫之声就环绕着整个山谷
Every full moon, the howling rings through the valley.
第二天早上 发现家畜被撕碎或生吞了
Next morning, livestock is found ripped apart and devoured.
这些故事只是用来掩饰偷盗行为的
Oh, tales like this just disguise the work of thieves.
偷了羊然后栽赃到狼身上 仅此而已
Steal the sheep and blame a wolf, simple as that.
但时常也会有小孩失踪
ROBERT: But sometimes a child goes missing.
每一代里都会有一个男孩从家里消失
Once in a generation, a boy will vanish from his homestead.
别去 孩子
ISOBEL: Don't, child.
你是谁
Who are you?
不要激怒他
Don't enrage him.
你来自哪里 你不是地球物种
Where are you from? You're not from Earth.
你来自哪个星球
What planet are you from?
聪明
intelligence.
你在哪里出生
Where were you born?
这躯体
This body?
十英里远
Ten miles away.
一个懦弱痛苦的男孩
A weakling, heartsick boy,
在晚上被我的信徒偷走了
stolen away at night by the Brethren for my cultivation.
我挖走了他的灵魂 寄宿于他的心脏
I carved out his soul and sat in his heart.
有人描述过那生物吗
Are there descriptions of the creature?
噢 有的 博士
Oh, yes, Doctor.
有各种图画和木雕
Drawings and wood carvings.
而且不仅仅是狼而已
And it's not merely a wolf,
比那严重得多
it's more than that.
是一个变成动物的人
This is a man who becomes an animal.
狼人
A werewolf?
好吧 这是人类的躯体
ROSE: All right, so the body's human.
那你呢 里面的东西呢
What about you, the thing inside?
家乡如此遥远
So far from home.
如果你想回家 我们可以帮忙
If you want to get back home, we can help.
我为什么要离开这里
Why would I leave this place?
工业世界 劳动力的世界 战争的世界
A world of industry, of workforce and warfare.
我能够大有作为
I could turn it to such purpose.
你要怎么做
How would you do that?
我会转移到圣君身上
I would migrate to the Holy Monarch.
你是指维多利亚女王
You mean Queen Victoria?
只要咬一口 我就能进入她的血液
With one bite, I would pass into her blood.
然后 狼的帝国就要开始了
And then it begins, the Empire of the Wolf.
问这么多问题
So many questions.
看 在你眼里 你也见过
Look! Inside your eyes. You've seen it, too.
见过什么
Seen what?
狼 在你体内有着些与狼有关的东西
The wolf. There is something of the wolf about you.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you mean.
你像太阳一样燃烧着
Oh, you burn like the sun,
但我所需要的是月亮
but all I require is the moon.
我父亲认为这不只是个传说
My father didn't treat it as a story. He said it was fact.
他说那是个事实
He said it was fact.
他甚至主张和那怪物交流 了解它的企图
He even claimed to have communed with the beast, to have learned its purpose.
我当初应该听他的话
I should have listened.
他的工作被阻碍了 出现了敌对者
His work was hindered. He made enemies.
圣凯瑟琳峡谷有一间寺庙
There's a monastery in the Glen of St Catherine.
那里的信徒反对我父亲的研究
The Brethren opposed my father's investigations.
也许他们认为他的工作违逆天意
Perhaps they thought his work ungodly.
我当初也这么想 但是现在我怀疑
That's what I thought, but now I wonder.
他们这么做也许还有别的原因
What if they had a different reason for wanting the story kept quiet?
如果他们背离了上帝 而崇拜狼呢
What if they turned from God and worshipped the wolf?
如果他们此刻正和我们在一起呢
And what if they were with us right now?
月光
Moonlight.
所有人 全都不要看他
All of you, stop looking at him.
弗洛拉 不要看
Flora, don't look,
听我说 抓紧铁链 然后拉
listen to me. Grab hold of the chain and pull!
加油 和我一起拉
Come on, with me! Pull!
我们不能 小姐 教徒禁止我们这样做
We can't, miss, we can't. The  Brethren forbid us
我说拉 别抱怨了 听我的 所有人都是
I said pull! Stop your whining and listen to me! All of yous!
也包括你 小姐 马上过来 拉
And that means you, your Ladyship. Now, come on! Pull!
这是什么意思 请做出解释
What is the meaning of this? Explain yourself, sir.
对不起 他们抓了我的妻子
I'm sorry, Your Majesty, they've got my wife.
洛斯在哪 她在哪
Rose, where's Rose? Where is she?
罗伯特爵士 过来
Sir Robert, come on!
加油 快拉
...three, pull!
一、二、三 拉
One, two, three, pull!
告诉我 先生 我要求知道你的意图
Tell me, sir. I demand to know your intention.
你到底想要什么
What is it that you want?
王座
The throne.
一、二、三 拉
ROSE: ...two, three, pull!
一、二、三
One, two, three,
拉
Dull!
你到底死哪儿去了
Where the hell have you been?
哇 漂亮极了
Oh, that's beautiful.
你们全都出去 走 走 走
Get out, all of you! Come on! Out! Out! Out!
先生 看来你阻碍了火车
I take it, sir, that you halted my train
是为了引我到这里来
to bring me here.
我们等待这么久
We've waited so long
就是为了等待你的的旅行碰上月圆之夜
for one of your journeys to coincide with the moon.
那你就白等了
Then you have waited in vain.
我这一生遭遇过六次暗杀
After six attempts on my life,
当然会有所准备
I am hardly unprepared.
我不觉得你会开枪 女人
Oh, I don't think so, woman.
正确的称呼应该是"陛下"
The correct form of address is "Your Majesty".
带上武器
Guns.
给我五支
I need five.
伊莎贝尔夫人 带着姑娘们从厨房出去
Lady Isobel, take the girls! Get them out through the kitchen.
杰克森 做好准备
Jackson, at arms...
我不能离开 你要做什么
I can't leave you. What will you do?
我一定要保护陛下
I must defend Her Majesty.
不要担心我了 走吧
Now, don't think of me, just go.
你们 都到我这儿来 过来
All of you at my side! Come on!
可能是任何光线调节型物种
Could be any form of light-modulating species
可以被特定波长激活
triggered by specific wavelengths.
它说过它想要什么没有
Did it say what it wanted?
王后 王冠 王座 你来说好了
The Queen, the crown, the throne, you name it.
开火
Fire!
打不开 他们把我们锁在里面了
It won't open. They've sealed us in.
噢 夫人 看
Oh, my lady, look.
他们不会让我们出去的
They'll never let us out.
我们死定了
They mean for us to die.
别这样说 弗洛拉
Don't say that, Flora!
好了 大伙们 我们撤退到楼上去 跟我来
All right, you men, we should retreat upstairs. Come with me.
我不会撤退 战斗结束了
I'll not retreat. The battle's done.
天底下没有生物能抵挡住这样的袭击
There's no creature on God's earth could survive such an assault.
我跟你说 快到楼上来
I'm telling you, come upstairs!
我跟你说 先生
And I'm telling you, sir,
我今晚要把这东西的皮挂到我墙壁上才睡
I will sleep well tonight with that thing's hide upon my wall.
它一定在垂死挣扎
It must have crawled away to die.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do!
不
No!
他们干掉它了吗
Did they kill it?
靠过来
Come close.
陛下 陛下
Your Majesty, Your Majesty!
罗伯特爵士 发生什么了
Sir Robert, what's happening?
我听到很吵闹的声音
I heard such terrible noises.
陛下 我们必须离开了
Your Majesty, we've got to get out.
安杰洛神父怎么了 他还在那儿吗
But what of Father Angelo, is he still here?
雷诺斯队长在处理他
Captain Reynolds disposed of him.
前门情况不好 堵住了
The front door's no good. It's been boarded shut.
抱歉 陛下 你得爬窗户出去了
Pardon me, Your Majesty, you'll have to leg it out of a window.
请恕我不顾礼节 陛下
Excuse my manners, ma'am,
但请让我走在前边 这样更好的帮助陛下
but I shall go first, the better to assist Her Majesty's egress.
多么高尚的情操 罗伯特爵士
A noble sentiment, my Sir Walter Raleigh.
你能不能快点啊
Yeah, any chance you could hurry up?
他们想让我们待在里面
I reckon the monky-boys want us to stay inside.
他们知道我是谁吗
Do they know who I am?
知道 那就是为什么他们想要你
Yeah, that's why they want you.
狼人把你困在这里是为了咬你一口
The wolf's lined you up for a biting.
现在别谈这些
Now, stop this talk.
不可能真的有狼人
There can't be an actual wolf.
我们要怎么做
What do we do?
我们…跑
We run.
就这样
Is that it?
你有没银子弹
You got any silver bullets?
当然没有
Not on me, no.
这不就得了 我们跑
There we are, then. We run.
陛下 作为医生 我建议来场小跑
Your Majesty, as a doctor, I recommend a vigorous jog,
对身体有好处
good for the health.
过来 过来
Come on. Come on.
我守在这里拦住它
I'll take this position and hold it.
你们继续跑 拜托
You keep moving, for God's sake.
陛下 我查看了那件物品 它被人拿走了
Your Majesty, I went to look for the property and it was taken.
盒子是空的
The chest was empty.
在我这里 它很安全
I have it. It's safe.
那你要好好的保重 陛下
Then remove yourself, ma'am.
博士 你一定要保护好陛下
Doctor, you stand as Her Majesty's protector.
你 罗伯特爵士
And you, Sir Robert.
你是皇室的叛徒
You're a traitor to the Crown.
子弹阻止不了它
Bullets can't stop it.
能给你们争取时间 马上跑
They'll buy you time. Now, run!
把门堵住
Barricade the door.
稍等一下 嘘
Wait a minute. Shh.
它停下来了
It stopped.
它走了
It's gone.
听
Listen.
这是唯一的门吗
Is this the only door?
是的
Yes.
不
No!
嘘
ROSE: Shh!
我不明白 什么阻止了它
I don't understand. What's stopping it?
这房间里的某种东西
Something inside this room.
是什么 为什么它不能进来
What is it? Why can't it get in?
告诉你吧
I tell you what, though.
什么
What?
狼人
Werewolf.
我知道
I know!
你还好吗
You all right?
我没事
I'm okay, yeah.
对不起 陛下
I'm sorry, ma'am.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
我应该把你送走
I should have sent you away.
我试过暗示您这里有问题
I tried to suggest something was wrong.
我指望您能察觉到
I thought you might notice.
你不觉得我的家丁有一点奇怪吗
Did you think there was nothing strange about my household staff?
他们全是光头 四肢发达
Well, they were bald, athletic.
你妻子不在 我还以为你很高兴
Your wife's away, I just thought you were happy.
顺便一提 陛下
I'll tell you what though,, ma'am,
我猜你现在并不觉得有趣
I bet you're not amused now.
你觉得这很有趣吗
Do you think this funny?
不 抱歉
No, ma'am, I'm sorry.
那是什么 我恳求哪个人来告诉我
What, exactly, I pray, tell me, someone, please,
那个生物到底是什么
what exactly is that creature?
你可能称之为狼人
You'd call it a werewolf,
但确切的说是狼型波长的混血人类
but technically it's more of a lupine-wavelength haemovariform.
我该信任你吗 阁下
And should I trust you, sir?
你 你能这么轻易地改变口音
You, who change your voice so easily?
你的口音怎么了
What happened to your accent?
噢 对了 抱歉
Oh, right, sorry, that...
我不相信
I'll not have it.
我不信你 不信那个生物 什么都不信
No, sir. Not you, not that thing, none of it.
这不是我的世界
This is not my world.
槲寄生
Mistletoe.
他们都戴着槲寄生花圈 狼人也不攻击他们
They're all garlanded in mistletoe and the wolf doesn't attack them.
谁把这个带到厨房来的
Who brought this into the kitchen?
一定是那些信徒带进来的
Must have been the Brethren.
收集起来 快 每一残片都要 马上
Gather it up, quickly. Every last scrap. Quick, now!
槲寄生
Mistletoe.
罗伯特爵士 那是你父亲放的吗
Sir Robert, did your father put that there?
不知道 我想应该是
I don't know. I suppose.
另外一个门也是
And on the other door, too.
可是雕刻应该不够
Though a carving wouldn't be enough.
我好奇
I wonder.
槲寄生 是槲寄生油
Viscum album, the oil of the mistletoe.
像油漆一样浸入木头里了
It's been worked into the wood like a varnish.
你父亲真聪明 我爱死他了
How clever was your dad? I love him!
强大的生物 槲寄生 充满了凝血素和毒肽
Powerful stuff, mistletoe, bursting with lectins and viscotoxins.
而且狼人对这个过敏
And the wolf's allergic to it?
或者它认为会过敏
Or it thinks it is.
那些光头僧侣需要一种控制狼人的方法
The monky-monk-monks need a way of controlling the wolf,
也许他们训练它对特定的东西做出反应
maybe they trained it to react against certain things.
不过 狼人并没打算放弃 博士
Nevertheless, that creature won't give up, Doctor,
而我们依然没有实在的武器
and we still don't possess an actual weapon.
没继承到你父亲的智慧 是吧
Oh, your father got all the brains, didn't he?
又开始没礼貌了
Being rude again.
很好 我正等你问呢
Good, I meant that one.
你想要武器 我们在书房里 书
You want weapons? We're in a library. Books!
世界上最好的武器
Best weapons in the world.
这房间就是最好的军械库
This room is the greatest arsenal we could have.
武装自己吧
Arm yourself.
没有狼的声音了 夫人 也许它走了
There's no sound of the wolf, my lady, perhaps it's gone.
也许它在耍我们
And perhaps it's toying with us.
我丈夫在上面
But my husband's up there,
如果他还有任何活着的可能 我一定要帮他
and if there's any chance he's still alive, then, by God, I'll assist him.
查寻生物学和动物学
Look up biology and zoology.
会有些关于狼的事
There might be something on wolves.
这个怎么样
DOCTOR: What about this?
一本专门讲槲寄生的书
A whole book on mistletoe.
火药的应用
ROBERT: "The application of gunpowder..."
如果我们能制造炸药
If we could build some form of explosive.
就是这样的东西
Hmm, that's the sort of thing.
噢
Ohhh.
看看你老爸发现了什么
Look what your old dad found.
从天而降的东西
Something fell to Earth.
太空船
A spaceship?
流星
Shooting star.
在基督1540年 詹姆斯五世统治时期
"In the year of our Lord 1540, under the reign of King James V,
有颗神奇的火球在深坑里燃烧
"an almighty fire did burn in the pit."
就在圣凯瑟琳峡谷 是那些僧侣地盘
That's the Glen of Saint Catherine, just by the monastery.
那是三百年前的事了 它在等待什么
But that's over 300 years ago. What's it been waiting for?
也许只有一个细胞活下来了
Maybe just a single cell survived.
一代一代缓慢适应着
Adapting slowly down the generations,
它通过人类存活下来
it survived through the humans,
寄生在不同的人身上
host after host after host.
为什么它想要王座
But why does it want the throne?
那就是它想要的
That's what it wants,
它是这么说的 "狼的帝国"
it said so. The Empire of the Wolf.
想像一下 如果维多利亚时代被加速
Imagine it. The Victorian Age accelerated.
烧煤的飞船和导弹 蒸汽驱动的机器
Starships and missiles fuelled by coal and driven by steam,
让历史在醒觉中崩溃
leaving history devastated in its wake.
罗伯特爵士
Sir Robert.
如果我死在这里
If I am to die here...
别那样说 陛下
Don't say that, Your Majesty.
我宁愿自杀也不让那畜生感染我
...I would destroy myself rather than let that creature infect me,
但那没关系
but that's no matter.
我只要求你能找到某个安全的地方
I ask only that you find some place of safekeeping
来保存一个比我更久远 比我更珍贵的东西
for something far older and more precious than myself.
没时间去担心你的贵重物品了
Hardly the time to worry about your valuables.
谢谢你的看法
Thank you for your opinion,
但没有什么比这更有价值了
but there is nothing more valuable than this.
噢 陛下
ROBERT: Oh, Your Majesty.
那难道是科依诺尔钻石
Is that the Koh-i-noor?
噢 是的
Oh, yes.
世界上最大的钻石
The greatest diamond in the world.
作为战争战利品送到我手中
Given to me as the spoils of war.
也许它的传说现在成真了
Perhaps its legend is now coming true.
传说拥有这钻石的人必死无疑
It is said that whoever owns it must surely die.
如果你能等 什么都会成真
Well, that's true of anything, if you wait long enough.
我能否
Can I?
真是太美了
That is so beautiful.
它值多少钱
How much is that worth?
据说是 整个星球一周的工资
They say, the wages of the entire planet for a whole week.
还好我妈不在这里
Good job my mum's not here,
为了这个 她能赤手空拳单挑狼人
she'd be fighting the wolf off with her bare hands for that thing.
而且她一定会打赢
And she'd win.
狼人去哪儿了
Where is the wolf?
这股寂静令人怀疑
I don't trust this silence.
为什么带着它旅行
Why do you travel with it?
我每年都会朝圣一次
My annual pilgrimage.
我要把它带给海勒和卡鲁
I'm taking it to Hellier and Carew,
皇家珠宝匠 在海兹海德
the Royal Jewellers at Hazlehead.
这宝石需要重新切割
The stone needs recutting.
但它很完美
But it's perfect.
我前夫并不这么想
My late husband never thought so.
事实就是
Now, there's a fact.
艾伯特王子不断地把这钻石拿去切割
Prince Albert kept on having the Koh-i-noor cut down.
以前比这还大40% 但他从未满意过
It used to be 40% bigger than this, but he was never happy.
继续切呀切
Kept on cutting and cutting.
他总是说光泽不太对劲
He always said the shine was not quite right,
但他死时还没完成
but he died with it still unfinished.
没完成
Unfinished.
噢 是的
Oh, yes!
这里还有好多未完成的事情
There's a lot of unfinished business in this house.
他父亲在研究 而你丈夫 陛下
His father's research and your husband, ma'am.
他来这里探寻这颗钻石
He came here and he sought the perfect diamond.
等一下 稍等
Hold on, oh, hold on.
所有这些零散的事
All these separate things,
他们根本不是零散的 它们相互联系
they're not separate at all, they're connected.
噢 我的头
Oh, my head, my head!
这房子 是为你设的陷阱 对吗
What if this house... It's a trap for you. Is that right, ma'am?
显然
Obviously.
至少 狼人就是这么打算的
At least, that's what the wolf intended,
但如果这是个陷阱中的陷阱呢
but what if there's a trap inside the trap?
解释一下 博士
Explain yourself, Doctor.
如果他父亲和你丈夫 并不仅仅是在讲故事
What if his father and your husband weren‘t just telling each other stories.
他们大胆设想这些事都是真的 并且想了应对措施
They dared to imagine all this was true, and they planned against it.
设置了真正的陷阱 不是对你 而是对狼人
Laying the real trap not for you, but for the wolf.
就是那只狼人
That wolf, there.
出去 出去 出去 出去
DOCTOR: Out! Out! Out! Out!
陛下
Your Majesty!
到天文台那里去
We've got to get to the observatory!
泼得好
Good shot!
这是槲寄生
FLORA: It was mistletoe.
伊莎贝尔
Isobel.
马上回到楼下去
ROBERT: Now get back downstairs.
保护好自己
Keep yourself safe.
亲爱的 走吧
My love. Now, go.
姑娘们 跟我来
Girls, come with me.
到楼下去 回到厨房 快点
Down the back stairs back to the kitchens, quickly.
走吧
Come on.
天文台在这边
The observatory is this way.
这里没有槲寄生
No mistletoe on these doors,
因为你父亲希望狼人进来
'cause your father wanted the wolf to get inside.
我需要时间 这儿没有什么可以做屏障吗
I just need time. Is there any way of barricading this?
你做你的事 我来抵抗它
Do your work, and I'll defend it.
如果我们能用绳子或什么把这里封住
If we could bind them shut with rope or something...
我说了 我给你争取时间 先生
I said I'll find you time, sir.
现在 快点进去
Now, get inside.
好样的
Good man.
陛下 钻石
Your Majesty, the diamond.
用来做什么
For what purpose?
这钻石最初的使命
The purpose it was designed for.
洛斯
Rose.
升起它 快点
Lift it, come on.
现在不是看星星的好时机啊
Not the right time for stargazing.
正是时候
Yes, it is.
我因为你犯了叛国罪
I committed treason for you,
但现在我的妻子 会记住我的荣誉
but now my wife will remember me with honour.
我是信仰的捍卫者 信仰也会捍卫我
I am the Defender of the Faith, and that Faith shall defend me.
记得你说过这是坏的
You said this thing doesn't work.
作为望远镜它是坏的 但它根本不是望远镜
It doesn't work as a telescope, 'cause that's not what it is.
这是储光室 它能放大光线 如同武器
It's a light chamber. It magnifies the light, like a weapon.
我们只需要把它充充能量
We've just got to power it up.
用什么 这里没有电
With what? There's no electricity.
月光
Moonlight.
但狼人需要月光 它是月光组成的
But the wolf needs moonlight. It's made by moonlight.
你70%的成分是水 但你照样会淹死 加油
You're 70% water, you can still drown. Come on!
加油
Come on!
让它再亮点 让我走
Make it brighter. Let me go.
陛下
Your Majesty?
它咬到你了吗
Did it bite you?
不是 只是割伤 就这样
No, it's... It's a cut, that's all.
如果那东西咬了你
If that thing bit you...
只是门裂开时的小木片弄的 没什么
It was a splinter of wood when the door came apart. It's nothing.
让我看看
Let me see.
没什么
It is nothing.
由教会和国家授予我的权力
By the power invested in me by the Church and the State,
我封你为塔迪斯博士爵士
I dub thee Sir Doctor of Tardis.
由教会和国家授予我的权力 我封你为
By the power invested in me by the Church and the State,I dub thee
鲍威尔庄园的洛斯女爵士
Dame Rose of the Powell Estate.
你们可以起来了
You may stand.
非常感谢 陛下
Many thanks, ma'am.
谢谢
Thanks.
回到家他们一定不会相信我们的
They're never gonna believe this back home.
陛下 昨晚你说到
Your Majesty, you said last night
收不到来自世界之外的讯息
about receiving no message from the great beyond.
我认为你丈夫切割钻石是为了救你的性命
I think your husband cut that diamond to save your life.
他到现在还在天堂守护着你 陛下
He's protecting you even now, ma'am, from beyond the grave.
确实
Indeed.
你也可以考虑一下这个
Then you may think on this also,
我认为这并不好笑
that I am not amused.
好啊
Yes!
一点都不好笑
Not remotely amused.
今后 我要放逐你们
And henceforth, I banish you.
什么
I'm sorry?
我已经奖赏过你们 博士
I have rewarded you, Sir Doctor,
现在你们要离开大英帝国 永远不得返回
and now you are exiled from this Empire, never to return.
我不知道你们是谁 或从哪来
I don't know what you are, the two of you, or where you're from,
但我知道你们和星空与魔法结交 并觉得那很有趣
but I know that you consort with stars and magic, and think it fun.
但你们的世界在恐惧、亵渎、和死亡颠峰上
But your world is steeped in terror and blasphemy and death,
我不会允许的
and I will not allow it.
你们要离开这些土地 希望你们会反省
You will leave these shores, and you will reflect, I hope,
在你们漂流时背离正道有多远
on how you came to stray so far from all that is good,
还有你们能在这些骇人生活中生存多久
and how much longer you may survive this terrible life.
马上离开我的世界
Now leave my world,
永远不要再回来
and never return.
哇
Whoa!
祝你愉快
Cheers!
走
Walk on.
有趣的是
No, but the funny thing is,
维多利亚的血液确实发生了突变
Queen Victoria actually did suffer a mutation of the blood.
这是历史事实 她是血友病患者
It's historical record. She was haemophiliac.
人们曾把那叫做皇家病
They used to call it the Royal Disease,
那一直是个谜 因为她不是遗传得到的
but it's always been a mystery because she didn't inherit it.
她父亲也没有 她母亲也没有
Her mum didn't have it. Her dad didn't have it.
就这样凭空出现
It came from nowhere.
你是说那是狼人咬的
What, and you're saying that's a wolf bite?
也许血友病只是一种委婉的称呼
Well, maybe haemophilia is just a Victorian euphemism.
狼人的婉称
For werewolf?
有可能
Could be.
维多利亚女王是狼人
Queen Victoria's a werewolf?
有可能
Could be.
她的孩子也得了皇家病
And her children had the Royal Disease.
也许她小咬了一下他们
Maybe she gave them a quick nip.
那么王室家族都是狼人
So the Royal Family are werewolves?
呃 也许现在还不是
Well, maybe not yet.
一个狼人细胞可能需要
I mean, a single wolf cell could take
一百多年才能成熟
100 years to mature.
可能要到…21世纪初期
Might be ready by, oh, early 21st century.
不 太扯了
No, that's just ridiculous.
注意 安妮公主
Mind you, Princess Anne.
我不多说了
I'll say no more.
如果你仔细想想
And if you think about it,
他们确实非常私密
they're very private.
他们都是预先计划好一切
They plan everything in advance.
他们可能真的按月亮来算时间
They could schedule themselves around the moon.
谁也说不准
We'd never know.
而且 他们喜欢打猎
And they like hunting.
他们爱好血腥的运动
They love blood sports.
噢 天呐 他们是狼人
Oh, my God! They're werewolves!
你要做什么 你会留在这里吗
What will you do? Will you stay here?
我不认为我能留下
I don't think I could.
我会卖掉它 或者拆掉它
I'd sell it, or pull this place down.
尽管我们不会公开这见事
Although we may not speak of these events in public,
但它们不会被遗忘的
they will not be forgotten.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
你丈夫的牺牲
Your husband's sacrifice,
他父亲的天才
the ingenuity of his father,
他们会永远长存
they will live on.
但怎么做到
But how?
昨晚 我看到
I saw, last night,
大不列颠存在着各种难以想像的敌人
that Great Britain has enemies beyond imagination,
我们必须全面保护我们的边界
and we must defend our borders on all sides.
我提议建立一个机构
I propose an institute
专门研究这些奇怪的事件 并与之做斗争
to investigate these strange happenings and to fight them.
我会这机构命名为"火炬木"
I would call it Torchwood.
火炬木研究院
The Torchwood Institute.
如果这个博士再回来 那么他得小心点了
And if this Doctor should return, then he should beware,
因为火炬木在等着他
because Torchwood will be waiting.
早上好 同学们
Good morning, class.
大家都坐好了吗
Are we sitting comfortably?
三个月前 厨房所有东西都被替换掉了
Three months ago, turns out all the kitchen staff were replaced.
看 有些事情在发生着
See? There's definitely something going on.
叫你回来果然是对的
I was right to call you home.
请让我为你介绍
May I introduce
莎拉·简·史密斯
Miss Sarah Jane Smith.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
是的 非常高兴
Yes. Very nice.
你在上班时间不可以随意离开你的岗位
You are not permitted to leave your station during a sitting.
班里的男生懂得远超地球水平的知识
Boy in class this morning, got knowledge way beyond planet Earth.
K-9
K9!
我们的时间到了 兄弟
Our time has come, my brothers.
今天我们将成为神
Today we shall become gods.